Register of the Nym Wales papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- CHINESE COMMUNISTS, 1936-1945, 1961 (Boxes 19-23)
  - Collected writings, 1934-1944 (Boxes 22-23)
    - Mao, Tse-tung
      - "Democracy and Revolution" or "The Obligation of the Chinese Anti-Japanese National United Front at the Present Stage," typescript, 1937 April 1 (Box-folder 23: 8)
      - "Mission of the Chinese Revolution after the Reunion of the Chinese Communist Party and Kuomintang," mimeograph, 1937 November (Box-folder 23: 9)
      - Speech abstract delivered before the Northwest Youth Salvation Representatives Congress, carbon copy of typescript in English, 1937 April 12 (Box-folder 23: 10)
      - Mao Tse-tung kuan yü t'ing chan k'ang Jih chih t'an hua, mimeograph, circa 1930 (Box-folder 23: 11)
        Contains talks by Mao concerning the ceasefire of the civil war and the fight against Japan.
    - "North China Unconquered," by C. P. (?), typescript with carbon copy, 1943 June (Box-folder 23: 12)
    - Pang, Teh hwei, "Conditions of Our Ultimate Victory in the Protracted War," mimeograph, 1937 December (Box-folder 23: 13)
    - "Reconstruction in Shensi-Kansu-Ninghsia Border Region," carbon copy of typewritten transcript of editorials and letters, 1942 June (Box-folder 23: 14)
    - Report on the activities of the Red Armies, carbon copy of typescript, 1936 December (Box-folder 23: 15)
    - "Report on the Central Hopei People's Self Defense Armies and the Political Organization Which They Are Fostering,", 1938 March (Box-folder 23: 16)
    - Shen-pei kung ch'an tang fa chan ti kai k'ang, carbon copy of manuscript, 1937 (Box-folder 23: 17)
      A report on the development of the Communist Party in Northern Shensi.
    - Shih-Ming, "Theory and Task of the New Political Stage--Summarized from the 'New Stage' written by Mao Tse-tung," carbon copy of typescript, undated (Box-folder 23: 18)
    - Snow, Edgar
      - Interview (partial) with Chou En-lai, carbon copy of typescript transcript, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 23: 19)
      - Notes on the organization and activities of the Chinese Red Army, handwritten and typescript, undated (Box-folder 23: 20)
      - "The Reds and the Northwest,", 1937 (Box-folder 23: 21)
        This article was read before the Men's Forum of the Peking Union Church and then published in the Shanghai Evening Post & Mercury in February of 1937. Includes a carbon copy of a typewritten transcript and printed copies.
      - "Will China Become a Russian Satellite?," Saturday Evening Post, undated (Box-folder 23: 22)
    - "Ten Years of the Red Army," handwritten translation, undated (Box-folder 23: 23)
    - Wen, Pin and Hsu, Meng-ch'iu, T'sung Hsi-ch'ang pa tzu tao An-shun ch'ang, 1936 (Box-folder 23: 24)
      Contains Long March personal narratives.
    - Yang, Te-chih, Chiang wo ti li shih hsieh tsai hsia mien, circa 1936 (Box-folder 23: 25)
      A handwritten autobiography of Yang Te-chih.
  - Magazine and journal articles, 1930s-1940s (Box-folder 23: 26)
  - News clippings, 1933-1950 (Box-folder 23: 27)
  - Book marks with portraits of Chinese Communist leaders and writers, 1937 (Box-folder 23: 28)
  - Miscellaneous, 1930s (Box-folder 23: 29)
- CHINESE LITERATURE, 1934-1937 (Boxes 24-27)
  Correspondence, writings, biographical material, and printed matter written and collected by Nym Wales and Edgar Snow in connection with a writing project concerning Chinese literature during the 1920s and 1930s. Some of the material in this series appeared in Living China (1937), edited by Edgar Snow with an essay by Nym Wales.
  - Correspondence of Nym Wales and Edgar Snow, 1934-1937 (Box 24)
    - Bennett, James W., circa 1937 (Box-folder 24: 1)
    - Carter, William D., 1937 (Box-folder 24: 2)
    - Chia, Wu, 1937 (Box-folder 24: 3)
    - Hall, Brian, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 24: 4)
    - Henle, Mr., 1935 (Box-folder 24: 5)
    - Herz, Henriette, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 24: 6)
    - Hsiao, Ch'ien, circa 1936-1937 (Box-folder 24: 7)
    - Hsu, S. S. (Lu Hsun Memorial Committee), 1937 (Box-folder 24: 8)
    - Lahmann, John, 1937 (Box-folder 24: 9)
    - Leiper, Maria, 1937 (Box-folder 24: 10)
    - Lin, Yutang, 1935 (Box-folder 24: 11)
    - Mao, Tun, undated (Box-folder 24: 12)
    - Marshall, A. Calder, 1937 (Box-folder 24: 13)
    - Pa, Chin, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 24: 14)
    - Peake, Cyrus H., 1937 (Box-folder 24: 15)
    - Sun, Hsi-chen, 1935 (Box-folder 24: 16)
    - Wen, Dr. Yuan-ming, 1934 (Box-folder 24: 17)
    - Yang, Ping, circa 1936-1937 (Box-folder 24: 18)
    - Yao, Hsin-nung, 1936 (Box-folder 24: 19)
    - Yuan, C. P., 1937 (Box-folder 24: 20)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box-folder 24: 21)
  - Writings, 1936-1937, undated (Box 24)
    Arranged by literary form and then chronologically.
    - Articles and essays
      - "The Modern Chinese Literary Movement,", 1936 June (Box-folder 24: 22)
        Contains typescript and carbon copy drafts, outlines, and a printed copy of the essay which was published in Living China.
      - Bibliography for Living China, carbon copy of typescript, undated (Box-folder 24: 23)
      - "The New Literature of 'Living China'," typescript, 1936 (Box-folder 24: 24)
      - "Literature and Revolution in China," carbon copy of typescript, 1937 February 9 (Box-folder 24: 25)
      - "Salute to Lu Shun," co-authored and edited by Edgar Snow, typescript with carbon copy, 1937 February 9 (Box-folder 24: 26)
        Written for Democracy magazine.
      - "The Chinese Short Story," typescript, undated (Box-folder 24: 27)
      - "Artists in Arms," carbon copy of typescript, undated (Box-folder 24: 28)
    - Book reviews, undated (Box-folder 24: 29)
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 24: 30)
      Also includes manuscript fragments and outlines.
  - Book review of Living China, undated (Box-folder 24: 31)
  - Collected correspondence, 1935-1937 (Box 25)
    - China League of Left Writers, 1935 March 11 (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - Franklin, Cecil, 1937 April 27 (Box-folder 25: 2)
    - Leiper, Maria (Simon and Schuster, Inc.), 1937 October 11 (Box-folder 25: 3)
    - Postgate, Raymond, undated (Box-folder 25: 4)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 25: 5)
  - Collected writings, 1930-1945, undated (Boxes 25-27)
    Comprised of short stories, plays, poems, autobiographical sketches, and articles.
    - Ai, Wu, 1938 (Box-folder 25: 6)
    - Buck, Pearl S., 1930-circa 1931 (Box-folder 25: 7)
    - Chang, T'ien-yi, undated (Box-folder 25: 8)
    - Chang, Tzu P'ing, 1935 (Box-folder 25: 9)
    - Chen, H. C., undated (Box-folder 25: 10)
    - Chen, L. J., 1938 (Box-folder 25: 11)
    - Ch'en, Shou-yi, 1936 (Box-folder 25: 12)
    - Chen, Ta-jin, undated (Box-folder 25: 13)
    - Cheng, Nung, undated (Box-folder 25: 14)
    - Chou, Wen, undated (Box-folder 25: 15)
    - Chung, Tang, undated (Box-folder 25: 16)
    - Fei, Jen-tze, undated (Box-folder 25: 17)
    - Hahn, Emily, undated (Box-folder 25: 18)
    - Howard, Harry Paxton, undated (Box-folder 25: 19)
    - Hsiao, Chien, 1942 (Box-folder 25: 20)
    - Hsiao, Hung, 1941, undated (Box-folder 25: 21)
    - Hsiao, K. C., undated (Box-folder 25: 22)
    - Hsiung, S. I., undated (Box-folder 25: 23)
    - Hsu, Ti-shan, undated (Box-folder 25: 24)
    - Hsu, Tsin-wen, undated (Box-folder 25: 25)
    - Hsu, Wen, undated (Box-folder 25: 26)
    - Hu, Shih, undated (Box-folder 25: 27)
    - Hu, Yeh-p'ing, undated (Box-folder 25: 28)
    - Irwin, Richard, 1938 (Box-folder 25: 29)
    - Kao Tao, undated (Box-folder 25: 30)
    - Lao, Shiang, undated (Box-folder 25: 31)
    - League of Left Writers of China, 1935 (Box-folder 25: 32)
    - Leung, George Kin, 1936 (Box-folder 25: 33)
    - Lin, Yutang, 1936 (Box-folder 25: 34)
    - Ling, Hsu Hua, 1936 (Box-folder 25: 35)
    - Liu, Chu Chien, undated (Box-folder 25: 36)
    - Lu, Hsün, 1935, undated (Box-folder 26: 1)
      Also known as Lu Sin, Lu Hsun, and Chou Shu-jen.
    - Mao, Tun, undated (Box-folder 26: 2)
    - Mei, Chung Fu, undated (Box-folder 26: 3)
    - Mu, Shih-ying, undated (Box-folder 26: 4)
    - Pa, Chin, 1936 (Box-folder 26: 5)
    - Ping, Hsi, undated (Box-folder 26: 6)
    - Sha, Ting, 1936 (Box-folder 26: 7)
    - Shen, Ts'ung-wen, undated (Box-folder 26: 8)
    - Shih, Ming (Yang Ping), undated (Box-folder 26: 9)
    - Siao, Emi, undated (Box-folder 26: 10)
    - Snow, Edgar, 1937, undated (Box-folder 26: 11-13)
      Includes a draft of the introduction to Living China " with biographical sketches of Chinese authors from 1937. Also included is an undated draft of an introduction to an unidentified work on Lu Shun, and an undated interview with Lu Shun.
    - Sun, Hsi-chen, undated (Box-folder 26: 14)
    - Tai, Ping-wan, undated (Box-folder 26: 15)
    - T'ien, Chun (Hsiao Chun), undated (Box-folder 26: 16)
    - Ting, Ling, 1935, undated (Box-folder 26: 17)
    - Tsao, Yu, 1936 (Box-folder 26: 18)
    - Tu, Fu, 1936 (Box-folder 26: 19)
    - Wang, Che-fu, undated (Box-folder 26: 20)
    - Wei, Chun-I, undated (Box-folder 26: 21)
    - Wells, Laura Preston, 1930 (Box-folder 26: 22)
    - Wu, Ch'iang, undated (Box-folder 26: 23)
    - Wu, K. T., 1936 (Box-folder 26: 24)
    - Yang, Kang, 1945 (Box-folder 26: 25)
    - Yao, Hsing-nung, undated (Box-folder 27: 1)
    - Yeh, Tzu, 1937 (Box-folder 27: 2)
    - Yu, P'ing-pe, 1936 (Box-folder 27: 3)
    - Yu, Ta-fu, 1936 (Box-folder 27: 4)
    - Miscellaneous poems, 1936-1938, undated (Box-folder 27: 5)
    - Miscellaneous short stories, 1935, undated (Box-folder 27: 6)
  - Biographical material, 1933-1937, undated (Box 27)
    - Chang, Tzu p'ing, undated (Box-folder 27: 7)
    - Chu, Hsiang, undated (Box-folder 27: 8)
    - Hsiao, Ch'ien, 1937 January 30 (Box-folder 27: 9)
    - Hsiao, Hung (Chang Nai-ying), undated (Box-folder 27: 10)
    - Hsu, Tsin, undated (Box-folder 27: 11)
    - Hu, Shih, undated (Box-folder 27: 12)
    - Jou, Shih, undated (Box-folder 27: 13)
    - Lu, Hsun, 1936, undated (Box-folder 27: 14)
    - Mu, Mu-t'ien, undated (Box-folder 27: 15)
    - Pa, Chin, undated (Box-folder 27: 16)
    - Shen, Yen-ping, undated (Box-folder 27: 17)
    - Shih, Ming, undated (Box-folder 27: 18)
    - Tien, Han, undated (Box-folder 27: 19)
    - Ting, Ling, 1933, undated (Box-folder 27: 20)
    - Tzu, Mo Hsu, 1933 (Box-folder 27: 21)
  - List of Chinese writers killed or imprisoned in the 1920s-1930s, undated (Box-folder 27: 22)
    Prepared by Mao Tun.
  - List of the board of directors of the Chinese National Writers and Artists Association, undated (Box-folder 27: 23)
  - Miscellaneous notes and clippings, 1934-1936, undated (Box-folder 27: 24)
- CHINESE ART, 1932-1936, 1960 (Box 28)
  Correspondence, writings, and biographical material collected by Nym Wales during her encounter with "left-wing" painters and poets during the early 1930s. A guide to the material, prepared by Nym Wales, appears at the beginning of the series.
  - "Notes on Left-Wing Painters and Modern Art in China," mimeograph, 1960 (Box-folder 28: 1)
    A guide to the material found in this series created by Nym Wales.
  - Correspondence, 1934-1936, undated (Box 28)
    - Cheng, Chen-to, 1935 (Box-folder 28: 2)
    - China Today, 1935 (Box-folder 28: 3)
    - Herz, Henriette, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 28: 4)
    - Lin, Yutang, 1935 (Box-folder 28: 5)
    - Snow, Edgar, 1935 (Box-folder 28: 6)
    - Walsh, Richard J., 1935-1936 (Box-folder 28: 7)
    - Wang, Chün-chü, 1934-1936 (Box-folder 28: 8)
    - Yang, Ping, undated (Box-folder 28: 9)
    - Yao, Hsing-nung, 1935 (Box-folder 28: 10)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, undated (Box-folder 28: 11)
  - Writings, 1932-1935, undated (Box 28)
    - Articles and essays
      - "An Exhibition of Paintings of Liu Hai-Sou," China Critic, 1932 November 3 (Box-folder 28: 12)
      - "Revolutionary Art in China," carbon copy of typescript, 1935 (Box-folder 28: 13)
      - "Chinese Artists Turn to the Masses," carbon copy of transcript, 1935 (Box-folder 28: 14)
        Published as "China's New Art" in Asia, July 1935.
      - "Revolution in China's Art," typescript draft, undated (Box-folder 28: 15)
    - Notes on left-wing painters and poets, undated (Box-folder 28: 16)
  - Collected writings, 1934-1936, undated (Box 28)
    - Wang, Chün-chü, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 28: 17-18)
      Contains copies of "The Four Gentlemen of China," published in Asia in December of 1935. It was edited with an introduction by Nym Wales. Also included in this file is a handwritten copy of "Present Day China's Art" in Chinese with a typewritten English translation. Authorship of this work is not certain.
    - Translations of "Left-Wing" poetry, circa 1934-1936 (Box-folder 28: 19)
    - Translations of communications by Association des Ecrivains et Artistes Revolutionaires and Andre Viollis, undated (Box-folder 28: 20)
  - Biographical material, undated (Box-folder 28: 21-22)
    Contains material on Liu Hai-Sou and Wang Chün-chü.
  - Miscellaneous printed material, undated (Box-folder 28: 23)
- GENERAL SUBJECT FILE, 1931-1961 (Boxes 29-33)
  Correspondence, writings, reports, memoranda, charts, maps, circulars, clippings, posters, and other printed matter dealing for the most part with the Far East, especially China. Arranged alphabetically by subject or issuing organization.
  - American Brotherhood for Cooperative Democracy, undated (Box-folder 29: 1)
  - American Committee for Non-Participation in Japanese Aggression, 1940, undated (Box-folder 29: 2)
  - American Labour Fund for Aid to China, Board of Custody, 1943, undated (Box-folder 29: 3-4)
    Includes a typescript draft of a memorandum on the use of American labor funds in China written by Nym Wales and other general material regarding the organization.
  - Americans in Shanghai, undated (Box-folder 29: 5)
    Contains an evacuation plan.
  - Anglo-Russian relations, undated (Box-folder 29: 6)
  - Baguio, Philippine Islands, 1937 (Box-folder 29: 7)
    Contains a directory and visitor's guide.
  - Bertram, James, 1940 (Box-folder 29: 8)
    Contains biographical material.
  - Bethune, Norman, 1940, undated (Box-folder 29: 9)
  - Chin tribes, 1931 (Box-folder 29: 10)
  - China, 1931-1946
    - General, 1931-1936, undated (Box-folder 29: 11-12)
      Contains news clippings as well as magazine and journal articles.
    - Commerce, 1930, 1938 (Box-folder 29: 13)
    - Constitutions, 1936 (Box-folder 29: 14)
      Contains a draft of a constitution beginning, "Chung-hua min kuo hsien fa ts'ao an."
    - Description and travel, undated (Box-folder 29: 15)
      Contains a carbon copy of a typescript draft of "Christmas in a Chinese Temple" by Nym Wales.
    - Economic conditions, 193-1942, undated (Box-folder 29: 16-17)
      Contains a general file as well as a handwritten manuscript in Chinese from the Kuomintang Financial Convention in Nanking. The opening lines of the manuscript translate to "Again some arbitrary propaganda..."
    - Famines, 1934 (Box-folder 29: 18)
      Carbon copy of manuscript in Chinese that translates to "Problems of famine in China."
    - History
      - Pre-1900, 1938, undated (Box-folder 29: 19)
      - Civil War, circa 1943-1945, undated (Box-folder 29: 20-22)
        Contains a general file on the civil war of 1945-1949 as well as typescripts of "Who Will Win the Civil War in China?" by Michael Lindsay and "The Question of Civil War in China" by Nym Wales.
    - Industries, 1938, 1946 (Box-folder 29: 23-24)
      Includes a general file as well as copies of "The Genius of China as seen in the Unit" written by Rewi Alley in August 1946.
    - Maps, 1934 (Box-folder 30: 1)
    - Politics and government, 1935-1944, undated (Box-folder 30: 2-5)
      Includes a general file, a copy of "China Needs True Democracy" (1943) by Chang Lan, a copy of "Freedom of Thought and the Ordinary Rule of Running a Government" by an unidentified author, and a list of "hsiens" in Hunan with a note from T. K. Wong to Edgar Snow.
    - Price and wage indexes, 1943 (Box-folder 30: 6)
    - Theater and the arts, 1933, undated (Box-folder 30: 7)
    - Women, 1938, undated (Box-folder 30: 8)
      Material focuses on women's role in society and the state.
  - China Aid Council, undated (Box-folder 30: 9)
  - China Council, undated (Box-folder 30: 10)
  - China Defense League, undated (Box-folder 30: 11-12)
    Includes a general file and posters.
  - Chinese Association of Labor, undated (Box-folder 30: 13)
  - Chinese in New Zealand, 1938 (Box-folder 30: 14)
    Contains an article by G. T. and Rewi Alley.
  - Chinese in the Pacific (Fiji to Hawaii), 1938 (Box-folder 30: 15)
    Includes an article by Rewi Alley.
  - Chinese (language), 1937 (Box-folder 30: 16)
    Includes a handwritten article in Chinese translated as "The New Chinese Character Movement in Northern China."
  - Chinese Journalists Association, 1936 (Box-folder 30: 17)
  - Chinese students abroad, 1943 (Box-folder 30: 18)
  - Citizens Committee to Repeal Chinese Exclusion and Place Immigration on a Quota Basis, undated (Box-folder 30: 19)
  - Citizens Committee to Welcome Madame Chiang Kai-shek, undated (Box-folder 30: 20)
  - Committee for a Democratic Far Eastern Policy, 1946-1948 (Box-folder 30: 21)
  - Committee for a Democratic Policy toward China, 1945 (Box-folder 30: 22)
  - Confucianism, 1930s (Box-folder 30: 23-26)
    Includes a general file, notes on the Confucian revival in China by Edgar Snow, and two drafts of articles by Nym Wales: "Back to California" and "New Life in Old China."
  - Democracy magazine, 1937, undated (Box-folder 30: 27-28)
    Includes correspondence as well as project material with writings by Nym Wales and Edgar Snow.
  - Donald, William Henry, 1938 (Box-folder 30: 29)
  - East and West Association, 1942 (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Education - China, 1932-1934, undated (Box-folder 31: 2-3)
    Contains a general file as well as an outline discussing education in times of emergency from the Peiping Cultural Circles National Salvation Group.
  - Fascism, circa 1930-1936
    - General, 1934 (Box-folder 31: 4)
    - Japan, 1934, undated (Box-folder 31: 5)
    - China (Blue Shirt Society), 1934-1936, undated (Box-folder 31: 6)
    - Snow, Edgar, "The Meaning of Fascism," Peiping Chronicle, 1935 January 9 (Box-folder 31: 7)
    - Wales, Nym, 1930s
      - "Confucian Fascism," (Box-folder 31: 8)
      - "Fascism in China," (Box-folder 31: 9)
      - "Fascist Development in China," (Box-folder 31: 10)
      - "The Fascist Movement in China," (Box-folder 31: 11)
      - "Kuomintang China: A Study in Colonial 'Sub-Fascism,'" (Box-folder 31: 12)
      - Miscellaneous notes and drafts (Box-folder 31: 13)
  - Flood Relief-China, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 31: 14-15)
    Contains a National Flood Relief Commission file and an article by Edgar Snow titled, "In The Wake of China's Flood," published in the New York Herald Tribune, December 6th, 1931.
  - France, 1930s (Box-folder 31: 16)
  - German interests in China, undated (Box-folder 31: 17)
  - Germany, 1930s (Box-folder 31: 18)
  - Great Britain, 1930s (Box-folder 31: 19)
  - Hahn, Emily, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 31: 20)
  - Hogg, George Aylwin, 1942 December (Box-folder 31: 21)
    Contains biographical material and a typescript by Nym Wales titled, "About George Aylwin Hogg."
  - Industrial cooperatives
    - India, 1942-1960 (Box-folder 37: 4)
    - Philippines, 1940 (Box-folder 37: 5-6)
      Includes articles on 20th century history of the Philippines, correspondence regarding industrial cooperatives there, and an address by Benito Razon at the Ateneo de Manila on July 24th, 1940.
  - Japan, 1931-1941 (Box-folder 31: 22)
  - Korea, 1939-1961 (Box-folder 31: 23-30)
    Includes a general file, a typescript by Changsoon Kim, and several writings by Nym Wales including, "Korea--America's Forgotten Ally," "Korea Is to Be Free and Independent," "Notes on Korea and the Life of Kim San," and "Rebel Korea." Also contains notes by Wales and a revision of an article for Britannica Junior.
  - Labouring Mutual Aid Society, undated (Box-folder 31: 31)
  - Literary criticism and book reviews, 1932-1941 (Box-folder 31: 32-33)
    Includes a general file as well as a piece by Nym Wales in the column "Dissenting Opinions" from the Saturday Review of Literature on January 31, 1942.
  - Manchuria, 1933-1936, undated (Box-folder 32: 1-3)
    Contains files on banditry, description and travel, and politics and government. Also included is an organizational chart of the Manchoukuo government.
  - Mitford Chemical Works, undated (Box-folder 32: 4)
  - Mohammed, 1932 (Box-folder 32: 5)
  - Mongolia, 1935, undated (Box-folder 32: 6)
  - National War Fund, undated (Box-folder 32: 7)
  - New China Information Committee, 1938 (Box-folder 32: 8)
  - New Life Movement, 1934-1939 (Box-folder 32: 9-10)
    Contains a general file and an article by Randall Gould titled, "A Foreigner Looks at the New Life Movement," published in Tien Hsia Monthly in November 1936.
  - Old China Hands, 1945 (Box-folder 32: 11)
    Includes a roster.
  - Opium, 1932-1933, undated (Box-folder 32: 12)
  - Philippine Civic League, undated (Box-folder 32: 13)
  - Philippine Islands, 1932-1940 (Box-folder 32: 14)
  - Refugees and war relief - China, 1938-1944, undated (Box-folder 32: 15)
    Includes material on International Peace Hospitals.
  - Shanghai, 1931-1936, undated (Box-folder 32: 16-19)
    Includes a general file, maps and descriptions, the 1934-1936 annual report for the Shanghai Municipal Council, and a reprint of an article about the Shanghai-Hangchow-Ningpo railroad by Edgar Snow and S. Y. Livingston titled, "Hangchow and Beyond."
  - Soong family, 1943 (Box-folder 33: 1)
    Includes biographical material.
  - Soviet-Japanese Neutrality Pact, 1944, undated (Box-folder 33: 2)
    Includes a draft of an article by Nym Wales titled, "The Soviet-Japanese Pact and the Far East."
  - Teheran conference, undated (Box-folder 33: 3)
  - United Peace Alliance, 1938 (Box-folder 33: 4)
  - US relations (general)
    - China, 1938-1952 (Box-folder 33: 5)
    - Japan, 1940, undated (Box-folder 33: 6-7)
      Includes a general file and "Must We Beat Japan First?" by Edgar Snow, which was published in Saturday Evening Post on October 24, 1942.
    - Philippine Islands, undated (Box-folder 33: 8)
  - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, 1933-1936 (Box-folder 33: 9)
  - Y.W.C.A. of China, 1940 (Box-folder 33: 10)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 33: 11-12)
- GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE OF NYM WALES AND EDGAR SNOW, 1935-1954 (Box 34)
  Contains miscellaneous correspondence, arranged alphabetically by correspondent or organization.
  - Araneta, Salvador (Philippine Civic League), 1940 (Box-folder 34: 1)
  - Changsoon, Kim (Korean American Cultural Association), 1942-1943 (Box-folder 34: 2)
  - Dudley, Marion, 1942 (Box-folder 34: 3)
  - Fortune Magazine (William D. Gear), 1942 (Box-folder 34: 4)
  - Fullsea, Wang, 1939 (Box-folder 34: 5)
  - Gould, Randall, 1941 (Box-folder 34: 6)
  - Griffin, David, 1940 (Box-folder 34: 7)
  - Herz, Henriette, 1935-1944 (Box-folder 34: 8)
  - Hsu, M. S., 1939 (Box-folder 34: 9)
  - Joy, Charles R. (Unitarian Service Committee), 1944 (Box-folder 34: 10)
  - Ladies Home Journal (Helen Schofield Luckas), 1954 (Box-folder 34: 11)
  - Lapwood, E. Ralph and Nancy (via the American Friends Service Committee), 1951 (Box-folder 34: 12)
  - Li, Min, 1939-1950 (Box-folder 34: 13)
  - Lim, Sian-tek, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 34: 14)
  - Lin, Jui chen, 1938 (Box-folder 34: 15)
  - London Daily Herald (Francis Williams), 1937 (Box-folder 34: 16)
  - National City Bank (Peiping), 1937 (Box-folder 34: 17)
  - Petrova, A., 1942 (Box-folder 34: 18)
    Petrova was secretary to the ambassador at the Embassy of the USSR in Washington, D. C.
  - Phillips, Dorothea, 1940 (Box-folder 34: 19)
  - Powell, J. B., 1936-1937 (Box-folder 34: 20)